totesport.com 2012-11-08

# totesport - security and privacy policy

**totesport** is a trading name of **Tote Credit Ltd.**

At totesport we take care to ensure that the information you provide to us is protected and managed in accordance with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998 and in accordance with the requirements of the Data Protection Laws of the Bailiwick of Guernsey and totesport is registered with Bailiwick of Guernsey Data Protection Office with the number 011567. This policy describes how information is gathered and used by totesport in the operation of this website.

## What information is collected?

The personal information you provide to us during the registration process and the subsequent records of your bets and account transactions are retained by us on our computer systems for the purposes of: 

  * enabling us to set up and manage your account;
  * building up a personal profile of you, including the events that you like to bet on;
  * providing you with useful information, such as promotional offers, technical updates, new features and information relating to other services offered by the Tote group; and helping us to improve the service we provide to you.

## Security

The sensitive information that you are required to give on the totesport registration form is encrypted and protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. We also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just sensitive information, is stored on servers in secure operating environments.

Your information will not be provided or sold to any third parties. totesport will only disclose your personal information to other companies within the Tote group, carefully selected suppliers that are engaged by totesport to process the information on our behalf or otherwise as required by law or the requirements of any applicable regulatory authority.

Also totesport may disclose your personal information to any body investigating actual or suspected criminal activity (including the Financial Services Authority and the National Criminal Intelligence Service) or, in respect of any event which we are taking bets on, any demonstrable threat to the integrity of that event and/or rules of the relevant governing bodies (including the Jockey Club in relation to UK horse racing, the ICC ACSU in relation to cricket and the UK football authorities in relation to UK football). In such event, totesport will only disclose personal information which it deems to be necessary and proportionate to any such investigation and where it has been assured by such third party that it will be used in compliance with data protection legislation.

## Under Age Gambling

It is against the law for persons under 18 to gamble. Therefore totesport reserves the right to carry out age verification checks on account holders who use payment mechanisms that are known to be legitimately available to under-18’s. Also, totesport may carry out age verification checks against a random selection of account holders regardless of the method of payment. Such checks will involve passing account holder information to third party agents. Anyone under the age of 18 found to be using the site will have their account closed instantly; winnings forfeited and will be reported to the police.

## Cookies

Transactions on our website automatically collect information using cookies. A cookie is a small file placed by a website on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to keep track of your browsing patterns and to build up a demographic profile.

## Accuracy

We will endeavour to ensure that the information we hold on you is accurate, relevant and up to date.

You may update your personal information at any time by logging in and selecting the Account option on the totesport Home page and then clicking on View/Amend Details.

## Data Protection Registration

totesport is a registered data controller under the UK Data Protection Act 1998, and is registered with Bailiwick of Guernsey Data Protection Office with the number 011567 under Section 19 of the Data Protection (Bailiwick of Guernsey) Law 2001 totesport complies with both the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and Data Protection (Bailiwick of Guernsey) Law 2001 in relation to the collection and processing of personal information.

## Changes to Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy we will post those changes here so that you are aware of any changes.

If you have any questions about the security of our website, or the information we hold on you, you can send an e-mail to [customercare@totesport.com](mailto:customercare@totesport.com "mail customer care").
